David Utrobin

Hi! I'm a professional based in Tampa, Florida with several years of experience in business development and operations. I have a deep passion for promoting powerful products by selling them or improving the organizations that produce them. I've worked in academia, ecommerce, and crypto.

- <u>David.utro@gmail.com</u>
- <u>GitHub</u>
- <u>LinkedIn</u>
- <u>Twitter</u>

Skills

My peers think I'm analytical, easy-going, charismatic, communicative, emotionally intelligent, and a reference for writing and operations best practices.

Below I list my hard skills, attributes, and tools I've worked with. I'm also experienced in project management methodologies, analytical exercises, and design methodologies.

Hard Skills	Attributes	Tools
budgeting	adaptable	airtable
call facilitation	analytical, creative, & critical thinker	diagrams.net
cryptocurrency wallet management	conflict resolver	excalidraw
editing & writing	emotionally intelligent	excel/sheets
interviewing	great sense of humor	figma
mediation & moderation	high integrity	git
note taking	large crypto industry professional network	jira
performance tracking	leads by example	lucid.app
policy design & enforcement	morale booster	mailchimp
project design & management	proactive	markdown
public speaking	punctual	photoshop
research	quick decision maker	trello
role & workflow design	reads a lot	vscode
strategic planning	sharp communicator	
team management	skeptical & truth oriented	
training		

Education

Bachelor's Degree in Corporate Communications, Baruch College (2011 - 2016)

Experience

Supportive LLC: Founder (2024/01 - current)

- Won Ajna as a client through a grant proposal.
- Launched ajnamatch.com, a matching site for borrowers and lenders as an attempt to solve a key UX problem.
- Pursue partners, projects, and interests on behalf of the Ajna Protocol.
- Serve as a voting delegate for the Grants Program.
- Advise, analyze, and vote on grant proposals.
- Create bi-annual reports on the state of the business.

Ajna: VP of Community and Grants (2023/01 - 2024/01)

- Created documentation; FAQs, ELI5, Whitepaper fixes, and more.
- Created a database of stakeholders.
- Developed relationships with builders, marketers, partners, and potential end users.
- Managed the online community properties; Discord and the Forum.
- Designed the Grants Program.
- Executed administrative plan for the Grants program.
- Created and maintained various trackers.
- Attended industry conferences to network and sell our product.

MakerDAO: Managing Director (2021/08 - 2023/01)

- Founded and led the <u>Governance Communications Core Unit</u>, a team focused on improving knowledge management and transparency by developing organization-wide programs.
- Conducted a winddown of the team and returned excess funds.
- Contributed to multiple organization improvement proposals.
- Identified needs, designed full and part-time roles, and sourced, interviewed, and onboarded 15 individuals.
- Facilitated weekly office hour calls.
- Led cross-team collaborations.
 - \bullet Led emergency communications support program.
 - Piloted cross-team project management initiative to train teams to follow SOPs for coordination of projects.
- \bullet Led program to create a GDPR-compliant stakeholder database.
- Led teamwide people management activities, including invoice payments, onboarding, payroll, performance monitoring, professional development, and recruitment.
- Managed a team of 15 with three direct reports.
- Moderated the public forums.
- \bullet Operated the team's multi-sig wallets.
- Participated in conferences and workshops.
- Performed parallel accounting and published monthly public financials.
- Raised over \$750,000 to fund the team.
- Supported organization-wide calls.
 - Created slide decks, banners, and thumbnails.

- Contributed to call strategy and improvement.
- Facilitated and co-facilitated calls.
- Underwent media & call facilitation training.

MakerDAO: MIP Editor (2021/05 - 2021/08)

- Advised proposal authors.
- Coordinated proposal-related actions with the governance team.
- Moderated the proposal forum category.
- Reviewed proposals and enforced formatting rules.
- Transfered proposals from the forum to the official git repository.

MakerDAO: Community Development Lead (2018/11 - 2021/05)

- Created and managed several community-growth-related projects.
- Edited and wrote copy including the MakerDAO FAQs.
- Hosted a <u>weekly community call series</u>, coordinating demos, Q&As, topic discussions, and interviews.
- Led a team that produced meeting minutes for public calls.
- Maintained a resource library called Awesome MakerDAO
- Operated a <u>meetup grants program</u> sponsoring over 200 events in 49 countries.
- Participated in conferences and workshops.
- · Recruited and advised contributors.
- Served on a committee that reviewed contributor project proposals.
- Underwent media training.

<u>Vitozon</u>: Operations Manager, Human Resource Officer (2017/02 - 2018/10)

- Assigned positions and tasks.
- Created and enforced standard operating procedures.
- Executed business improvement plans.
- Managed human resource-related activities, including compliance, onboarding, payroll, performance monitoring, and recruitment.
- Managed customer service needs.
- Worked with our software engineer to develop the back-end logistics system.

Baruch College: Program Administrator (2016/01 - 2017/07)

- Assisted fundraising efforts by scheduling dinners, identifying potential donors, and writing messages.
- Drafted agendas for meetings.
- Drafted and advised on various documents such as grant proposals, reports, memos, and more.
- Managed Director's schedule.
- Managed program's Facebook group.
- Processed reimbursements for the program.
- Sat in on classes.

Baruch College: Teacher Assistant (2015/09 - 2016/01)

- Assisted a course called "Organizations, Ethics, and Leadership", taught by
 Professor Bruce Lloyd Payne, which dissected a dozen short stories and treated
 them like case studies for exploring leadership ethics, dilemmas, successes,
 and failures.
- Advised students on the course and their term projects.
- Graded in-class quizzes and essay assignments.

New York Cares: Data Analysis & Site Design Intern (2015/09 - 2016/01)

- · Analysed database information to identify problems within volunteer programs.
- Collaborated on projects including survey revisions, home page redesign, and data illustration.
- Reviewed volunteer evaluations.

Every Nation: Sound & Equipment Engineer, Service Coordinator (2012/10 - 2017/06)

- Coordinated logistics for the Sunday evening church service.
- Oversaw all volunteer efforts for the evening service.
- Operated sound boards & stage lighting panels, fine-tuned audio for various venues and set up and packed away equipment.

Public Appearances & Content

- <u>Tutorial: Ajna x Summer.fi: DeFi Lending & Borrowing against Anything!</u> (2024/02)
- YouTube Playlist that includes 117 public calls I hosted for MakerDAO (Call Host, 2018/11 2021/04)
- [AMA] Communicating Governance with David Utrobin (Video Interview, 2021/07)
- Whiteboard Series with NEAR | Ep: 10 David Utrobin from MakerDAO (Video Interview, 2019/03)
- <u>POV Crypto Special Edition The Role of Ether in Multi-Collateral DAI</u> (*Podcast guest, 2018/12*)
- How Does MakerDao's Proposed 20% Charitable Giving Principle Make Sense? (Published article, 2018/07)
- The Importance of Debt Ceilings within MakerDAO's Collateralized Stable-Coin System (Published article, 2018/04)